You think you know the story.
The Cabin in the Woods is a horror, mystery,
comedy film directed by Drew Goddard.
Five friends set out for a weekend at a remote cabin in the woods,
expecting nothing more than fun and relaxation.
As night falls, they discover that something far more unsettling is at
work and that nothing about their getaway is what it seems.
Dana Polk, played by Kristen Connolly.
Marty Mikalski, played by Fran Kranz.
Curt Vaughn, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Holden McCrea, played by Jesse Williams.
Jules Louden, played by Anna Hutchison.
Richard Sitterson, played by Richard Jenkins.
The Cabin in the Woods is a 2011 science fiction comedy horror film directed by Drew Goddard in
his directorial debut, produced by Joss Whedon, and written by Whedon and Goddard.
It stars Kristen Connolly, Chris Hemsworth, Anna Hutchison, Fran Kranz,
Jesse Williams, Richard Jenkins, and Bradley Whitford.
The plot follows a group of college students who retreat to a remote cabin in the woods where they fall victim to a
variety of monsters while technicians manipulate events from an underground facility for a global purpose.
Goddard and Whedon, who previously worked together on Buffy the Vampire Slayer and Angel, wrote the screenplay in three days,
describing it as an attempt to "revitalize" the slasher film genre and as a critical satire on torture porn.
The special effects, monster costumes, special makeup, and
prosthetic makeup for the film were done by AFX Studio.
Filming took place in Vancouver, British Columbia, from March to
May 2009 on an estimated budget of $30 million.
The film was originally slated for release on October 23, 2009, which was later delayed to February 5, 2010, by
Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM) and United Artists (UA), but was indefinitely shelved due to financial difficulties.
In 2011, Lionsgate Films picked up the distribution rights.
The film premiered in December 2011 at the Butt-Numb-A-Thon film festival in Austin, Texas and was
released in the United States on April 13, 2012, to critical and commercial success.
It grossed  $66.5 million worldwide, and received generally positive reviews
from critics, who praised its screenplay, tone, and performances.
The film explores themes of giant snake, school party,
motorcycle crash, abandoned house, woods.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and mind_bending.